<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Honeydukes</title>
  <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-19T21:10:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://welkinblue.github.io</id>
  <author>
    <name>JL</name>
    <email>elrohirrocks007@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Les Meninas</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2015/11/19/a-discussion-on-las-meninas.html"/>
    <updated>2015-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2015/11/19/a-discussion-on-las-meninas</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Las_Meninas,_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez,_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg#/media/File:Las_Meninas,_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez,_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/31/Las_Meninas%2C_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez%2C_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg/1200px-Las_Meninas%2C_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez%2C_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Las Meninas, by Diego Velázquez, from Prado in Google Earth.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Las_Meninas,_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez,_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg#/media/File:Las_Meninas,_by_Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez,_from_Prado_in_Google_Earth.jpg&quot;&gt;Las Meninas, by Diego Velázquez, from Prado in Google Earth&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by &lt;a href=&quot;//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diego_Vel%C3%A1zquez&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;en:Diego Velázquez&quot;&gt;Diego Velázquez&lt;/a&gt; - The Prado in Google Earth: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.google.com/intl/en/landing/prado/&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt; - 7th level of zoom, JPEG compression quality: Photoshop 8.. Licensed under Public Domain via &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/&quot;&gt;Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Essay for an art history class, slightly modified)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s Las Meninas. Created during High Baroque period in Spain, ca. 1640-65, this masterpiece now resides in Museo Prado, Madrid. Velázquez not only incorporated all Renaissance and Baroque techniques in it, he also revolutionized the idea of what art can convey. This painting also promoted him to a high social status, therefore is certainly a great piece of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the center, the Infanta Margarita is accompanied by two maids of honor, Isabel and Maria, one offering her water, the other courtesying. Next to them, Velázquez himself is holding a painting brush and a palatte. In the foreground, we see the Infanta&amp;rsquo;s favorite dwarfs, one of them putting a foot on the royal family&amp;rsquo;s dog. The dog&amp;rsquo;s calm reactions indicates the close relationship between the family and the dwarfs. Behind them, there is a court lady dressed like a widow, and Diego Luiz, a chaperone. In the far back, Don José, the chamberlain is frozen in his movement, about to enter a doorway. To his right, a mirror reflects King Philip IV and Queen Mariana, also his niece (interesting history of the Habsburg family). All of our subjects are in Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s studio in the Royal Alcázar Palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this painting, Velázquez demonstrates many typical Baroque characteristics. He uses a certain degree of tenebrism, casting spolight on his subjects, especially the Infanta. They are brightly illuminated against the dark background. This dramatic contrast between light and dark draws the viewer into the scene. He also created strong diagonals in the pictures, which add to the dramatic effect. Don José in the back is about to turn; he is rendered as in the middle of a movement, giving viewers a sense of anticipation. He also stands out from the brightly illuminated doorway, which makes him stands out particularly. Most subjects are looking at the viewers as the latter look at them. This mutual awareness is very subtle. Velázquez brings interactions in Baroque art to a new level: he created an extension of pictorial depth in both directions. The doorway and the ascending staircase creates a space that leads viewers back; the outward glances incorporate the viewers&#39; space into the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s work also distinguishes itself from other Baroque compositions in that he adopts many innovative techniques. He uses impasto, applying very thick paint at certain places to create realistic textures. For instance, the Infanta&amp;rsquo;s silver, shiny dress displays a smooth, light and glittering texture, because the artist carefully applied thick and short strokes. We can even see the buttons on her chest. Velázquez also uses different strokes at other places. For instance, thinenr strokes are used to render the girl&amp;rsquo;s thin, smooth hair. Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s attention to these details made him a great child portrait painter. In the mirror reflection of the royal couple, we can see a red drapery over their heads, which implies that they are at the viewers&#39; position, posing for a portrait. This is because red draperies were common in royal or noble portraits. Here, Velázquez wants to tell that the mirror reflects both the portrait he&amp;rsquo;s painting and the real people. He wants to convey that his paintings are indistinguishable from real subjects. Further, it is also hard to tell the border between his hand and the painting brush he&amp;rsquo;s holding - he wants to show that his skills are so extraordinary that the pen is onlyl a natural extension of his hand. These clever implications are unique to Velázquez, therefore making this painting a classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth noticing that this painting was not commissioned by the royal family. At the time of the painting, Velázquez wanted to promote himself and his profession. More specifically, Velázquez wanted to join the Order of Santiago, an order of knights that only accpeted those of noble lineage. As a commoner artist, Velázquez decided to &amp;ldquo;paint his way in.&amp;rdquo; He used his art, especially Las Meninas to promote himself; thus the implication of his skills in the painting as previously explained. He did obtain the membership of the Order eventually, and to mark this triumph, he added the Order&amp;rsquo;s red insignia of a dagger and a cross to his chest in the painting. This painting was possible also because King Philip IV was a generous patron of art and had a good relationship with Velázquez, supporting his work all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s all-encompassing Las Meninas hightlights the techniques in Baroque art, generating a realistic, dramatic scene with subtile interactions with viewers. He also transcended other Baroque art by intelligently adding innovative techniques and ideas to make this painting more interesting. His effort gained him the honor of joining the Order of Santiago, and also inspired many generations to come. Velázquez, King Philip IV and the Count-Duke Olivares created the Golden Age of Spanish Baroque painting. Without Velázquez&amp;rsquo;s skills, or the other two&amp;rsquo;s patronage, we would not have seen such an abundance of breath-taking Spanish Baroque art today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hacker Night</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2015/09/19/hacker-night.html"/>
    <updated>2015-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2015/09/19/hacker-night</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Friday, my friends and I built a small unity game called Publiclash for Hacker Night, a warm-up before VandyHacks II. Publiclash is a one-on-one shooting game where the player who gets most points from hitting the target wins. Our game won the first place after a vote. The prize is a MINECRAFT light-up redstone ore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5627/21626775811_93898b45fa_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks awesome! Though to open the battery compartment I&amp;rsquo;ll need a screwdriver, which I don&amp;rsquo;t have. After experimenting with a variety of tools (credit cards, coins, scissors, forks, paper clips, you name it&amp;hellip;), I just decided to let the ore sit there for a while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Snappy is the winner!</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2015/08/04/snappy-is-the-winner.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2015/08/04/snappy-is-the-winner</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Snappy is part of STORM Lab&amp;rsquo;s eSMAC project I&amp;rsquo;m working on. It&amp;rsquo;s an educational modular robot for high school STEM courses. It comes with different modules, including a rechargeable battery, a BLE module, a barometer, a temperature sensor and a gyroscope. Snappy can be used to teach students basic programming, or it can be put in a water rocket (which is often used in a high school physics class) to measure the height and speed of the rocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My supervisor, Eka, the post doc of our lab participated in Your IoT | Connected World Contest with Snappy in July and won a prize of $10k of component to spend on Digikey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details of the robot, here is the award-winning video of &lt;a href=&quot;http://youriotcontest.com/entry/9296391&quot;&gt;Snappy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Baxter the Master Chef</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2014/12/15/baxter-the-master-chef.html"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2014/12/15/baxter-the-master-chef</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A video of my class project - Baxter the Master Chef. Baxter&amp;rsquo;s program is written in Python. It takes a photo of the ham, does some image processing to locate the geometric center of the ham, and then the cutting starts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/139166469&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Guide to Writing about Art History with Walter Benjamin</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2014/03/20/a-guide-to-writing-about-art-with-walter-benjamin.html"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2014/03/20/a-guide-to-writing-about-art-with-walter-benjamin</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my Western Civilization class today, we were introduced to a critique written by Walter Benjamin, a German philosophor who had tremendous influence on 20th century western art and aesthetic theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This critique stays true to his reputation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Klee painting named Angelus Novus shows an angel looking as though he is about to move away from something he is fixedly contemplating. His eyes are staring, his mouth is open, his wings are spread. This is how one pictures the angel of history. His face is turned toward the past. Where we perceive a chain of events, he sees one single catastrophe which keeps piling wreckage upon wreckage and hurls it in front of his feet. The angel would like to stay, awaken the dead, and make whole what has been smashed. But a storm is blowing from Paradise; it has got caught in his wings with such violence that the angel can no longer close them. The storm irresistibly propels him into the future to which his back is turned, while the pile of debris before him grows skyward. This storm is what we call progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beautifully written and brings a vivid rendering of the angel to my mind. Out of curiosity I decided to look it up - the real painting must be far more stunning than what I have imagined it to be. So I googled Angelus Novus&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Benjamin purchased a Swiss-German painter, Paul Klee&amp;rsquo;s drawing of the Angel fo History in 1921 for quite a fortune, and it remained his most prized possession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It certainly is a very interesting drawing&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Just a bit different from what I have pictured&amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It looks like&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Wait, are you sure about this?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Okay.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to say no.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Since you are so curious&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;After all this is a world of possibilities&amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;There you go.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Klee,_paul,_angelus_novus,_1920.jpg#/media/File:Klee,_paul,_angelus_novus,_1920.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4b/Klee%2C_paul%2C_angelus_novus%2C_1920.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Klee, paul, angelus novus, 1920.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Klee,_paul,_angelus_novus,_1920.jpg#/media/File:Klee,_paul,_angelus_novus,_1920.jpg&quot;&gt;Klee, paul, angelus novus, 1920&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by &lt;a href=&quot;//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Klee&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;en:Paul Klee&quot;&gt;Paul Klee&lt;/a&gt; - The Israel Museum, Jerusalem. Licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0&quot; title=&quot;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/&quot;&gt;Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Walter Benjamin would probably make a very successful commercial designer if he was still alive today&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Vandy in Fall</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2012/10/19/vandy-in-fall.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2012/10/19/vandy-in-fall</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/11254711_864512160309648_2104348753_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/11084975_643007349168079_2126390983_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/11186884_1482215168735575_1008971767_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Michael</title>
    <link href="http://welkinblue.github.io/2012/10/16/michael.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>welkinblue.github.io/2012/10/16/michael</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The human narrative is replete with memorable characters like America&amp;rsquo;s Paul Revere, ancient Greece&amp;rsquo;s Perseus, or the Fox Spirits of East Asia. Imagine one of humanity&amp;rsquo;s storied figures is alive and working in the world today. Why does Rapunzel work at Saks? Would Shiva be a general or a diplomat? Is Quetzalcoatl trapped in a zoo? In short, connect your chosen figure to the contemporary world and imagine the life he/she/it might lead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember how exactly he came to this world, nor when. But he still recalled the days with other archangels in heaven, in the light of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he left for the land of Adam’s heirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael checked his schedule again, making sure that he had remembered all his appointments correctly. He then submitted the case report to his boss, while waiting for his often-late partner to come to work. Ten years of work has made him a veteran of investigation and detection, and of course, the star agent of Criminal Investigative Division of FBI Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His weapon: a Glock 22, which felt just like his sword from when he was still the commander of the angel legions. He could tackle his targets easily with only a few moves. And he was fast, really fast, thanks to the endless battles with the devil’s armies, who were hundreds of times faster than humans, and far more savage. He had finished thousands of cases in his ten years at the Bureau, and had never taken a single day off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All set?&amp;rdquo; Michael’s partner Dean – a dashing twenty-some, recently transferred from New York, thanks to his talent for trouble making – knocked on his desk. He gave a brief nod and jogged out of the headquarters with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael had never seen a more disturbing case. The victims were killed in an extremely cruel way. Every one of them was paralyzed and then tortured to death. The criminal left nothing at the scene but his signature: a bloody butterfly mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stefan Crawley, 26, Caucasian, 5&#39;7&amp;rdquo;, blonde hair, and dark brown eyes. Found dead this morning by his neighbor. Fifth victim of the same M.O. – serial murder confirmed.&amp;ldquo; After examining the fresh scene, Michael realized that he would have to give up home cooking and order takeout Chinese again. Pity for the pork chops he defrosted this morning. The Bureau really owed his stomach extra allowance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He found a small piece of unidentified fabric when his cellphone started to scream, breaking the dead silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of our informants just called, saying he’s got reliable evidence. Meet him at House of Blues, Sunset Boulevard at 9:00 pm today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City of Angels, Michael smiled to himself as he drove along Sunset Boulevard. Should be &amp;ldquo;of Lost Angels,&amp;rdquo; flamboyant yet enthralling. He painstakingly parked the car, and stepped into the dark dreamy bar, searching for the informer. Though named the House of Blues, this place was full of strong beats and the inviting smell of jambalaya and bread pudding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went upstairs to avoid the crowd and get a panoramic view from the balcony. His eyes soon grasped something. As the tall and lean figure turned around gently, Michael recognized a familiar face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late archangel Lucifer now stood in front of him.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>JL</name>
      <uri>http://welkinblue.github.io/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
</feed>